My name is Shawn Connolly and I'm from San Fransisco, California, and I run a program called the SF Skate Club, which teaches kids how to skate.
Now, what I'm explaining to you today is a backside 180 ollie.
Backside 180 ollie's shouldn't be tried until you learn how to do your straight ollie's very well.
And you also need to know how to roll backwards just a little bit to be able to do this trick well.
Now, you set up pretty much the same as you do for an ollie, with your foot planted on the tail, because with your toe directly on the tail to get as much pop as possible, and you're front foot is going to be right in the middle of the board, so that you're able to get a lot of pop and nice control.
Now, after that, the rest of the backside 180 ollie relies on you following through with your body and your shoulders.
Basically, the upper body tells the lower body what to do and how to get over to it.
So you build up the momentum with your shoulders, and you spin around in the air after you've hit your ollie.
Now, you're going to want your body to be well beyond the 180 position before you even get the tail on the ground, and this is going to help you get all the way around.
Now, you will hit your tail, follow through with the shoulders, and pop your back wheels off the ground and all the way around.
At first you're going to notice that you may end up pivoting with your front wheels, and with your foot on the nose to get yourself all the way around.
Now, that's usually how you learn how to do it, but eventually you're going to want to ollie, 180 and land with out pivoting, and land continue rolling fakie.
Now, with the backside 180 ollie, what makes it different from the front side 180 ollie is that you're going in a direction that you can't see.
So, you're heading around and you can't see which way you're going.
So after you land, you're going to want to turn yourself back around, and look in the direction that you're headed, rolling fakie.
My name is Shawn Connolly and I live in San Fransisco, California, and I run a skateboard program for kids called the SF Skate Club.
You can find out more about it at sfskateclub.com.